<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Leah Petersen</title>
    <description>Motorcycle stunt woman turned developer, DevOps Engineer specializing in Kubernetes.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2018 15:35:11 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2018 15:35:11 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Basic Linux Concepts</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Basic Linux Concepts&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-is-linux&quot;&gt;What is Linux?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Linux is a computer operating system. An operating system is a software layer that coordinates between you computer’s hardware (CPU, memory and devices like keyboards and mice) and the applications you use (web browsers, word editors or games). Other common operating systems are Windows or Mac OXS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;is-linux-the-same-as-unix&quot;&gt;Is “Linux” the same as “Unix”?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UNIX is an operating system developed in the 1960’s. Today the term “Unix” is used to describe any operating system that conforms to the Unix standard, meaning the core operating system operates the same as the original Unix operating system. “Unix-like” is a general term, with no official definition, used to describe software that behaves similar to Unix. Linux and MAC OSX are both “unix-like”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-is-a-linux-distribution&quot;&gt;What is a “Linux Distribution”?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Linux distros” are different flavors of Linux. Ubuntu and Fedora are popular distributions. Distributions come with different “package managers”, capabilities and strengths. Some distributions are better for certain scenarios or workloads. Be aware each distribution has different tools and functions - if you are trying to accomplish something be sure to include the distro in your google search, ie: “How to install vim on debian linux”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-is-a-package-manager&quot;&gt;What is a “package manager”?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A package manager will assist with keeping track of what programs are installed on your computer, make it easy to install new programs and upgrade programs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;and-what-is-the-linux-kernel&quot;&gt;And what is the Linux “kernel”?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not popcorn related (unfortunately), all Linux distributions use the same Linux kernel. The kernel is the lowest level of software that interfaces with your computer’s hardware. One of the kernel’s main jobs is the manage resources like CPU, memory and IPC &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Inter-process_communication&quot;&gt;“Inter-process communication”&lt;/a&gt;. There are three common types of kernels: microkernel, monolithic kernel and hybrid kernel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;microkernel&lt;/strong&gt; really just cares about CPU, memory and IPC and can complete all its functions in “supervisor mode” (also known as kernel mode). Everything else your computer needs to function is considered an “accessory” and is run in “user mode” (more about that below). This type of kernel makes it harder for the applications to interact with your computers hardware, but in the end it is more secure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;monolithic&lt;/strong&gt; kernel deals with managing resources in addition to device drivers, file system management, and system server calls. Monolithic kernels deal with all these concerns in “supervisor mode” which allows for more direct communication with the hardware but that benefit makes monolithic kernels less secure than microkernels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/gV8hn.png&quot; alt=&quot;kernel image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Linux kernel is an open-source monolithic Unix-like computer operating system kernel (hey, we should understand all those words by now).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;why-do-people-and-companies-use-linux&quot;&gt;Why do people and companies use Linux?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Linux is open source software - unlike Windows or Mac OXS. This means the code for Linux is open to the public for people or companies to modify or extend to meet their requirements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Linux is a free and flexible operating system, there are many kinds of Linux distributions which offer different bundles of tools and capabilities. Lots of governments run Linux on their computer - it’s free! Computers hosting websites or applications commonly run use Linux, as do computers tasked with automated testing or serving media.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2018/Basic-Linux-Concepts/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018/Basic-Linux-Concepts/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What is TCP/IP?</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;introduction-to-tcpip&quot;&gt;Introduction to TCP/IP&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-is-tcpip&quot;&gt;What is TCP/IP?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Transmission Control Protocol (TCP) and Internet Protocol (IP) are two separate computer network protocols. Together they create a “suite” of protocols known as the Internet Protocol Suite (ICP) which is the conceptual model and set of communications protocols used to create the Internet. More plainly put, these are a set of rules that help the internet move data between computers. There are two concepts that can help you understand how the internet moves data quickly but also precisely - &lt;strong&gt;“stateless” and “stateful”&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stateless means systems can do each job without worrying if the jobs before were successful. It’s like if you were working the window at a fastfood restaurant and you just grabbed a bag of food and threw it out the window not caring if the right person got the right bag of food. You could work as fast as the bags of food came to you. “Stateful” on the other hand means you need to be responsible for the whole lifecycle of the job. Did it get to where it was routed and did it arrive in the correct state? So, is each person getting the bag of food they ordered - you can see how that might slow down your work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TCP&lt;/strong&gt; defines how applications communication across a network, how to break down a message into smaller “packets” for expedited transmission and how to reassemble them at the destination address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IP&lt;/strong&gt; defines how to address and route each packet to the right destination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Put TCP and IP together you can systematically move data from one computer to another - the internet!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a four layer “TCP/IP Model” that describes the responsibilities of moving data between computers. The layers are application, transport, internet and data link. The two computers communicating are in a client/server relationship, the client requests a service or resource (for instance your computer is the client when you turn on your browser and type in Reddit.com) and a server who will return that data (cat memes from reddit).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each layer in the TCP/IP model include more protocols to help each layer fulfill its responsibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;application layer&lt;/strong&gt; is responsible for standardizing data exchange. At this layer websites use Hypertext Transfer Protocol (HTTP) to transfer web pages. This layer might also use File Transfer Protocol (FTP) to move files or Simple Mail Transfer Protocol (SMTP) for email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;transport layer&lt;/strong&gt; is responsible for end to end communication across the network (the request of the cat meme to the cat memes arrival at the destination). This layer uses TCP generally, but User Datagram Protocol (UDP) is another option that is a bit faster and used for applications like online games.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The application layer and the transport layer communicate via “ports”. A port is a “logical connection place” and your computer has physical ports, that allow external devices like keyboards and USBs to be connected and virtual ports. We are talking about these virtual ports. Information flowing to your computer will be routed through a port. Data will show up using your computer’s IP address and it will be processed into something known and useful through the port. The application can assign specific protocols to specific ports, so the transport layer knows what to expect. There are some known ports that are assigned by the Internet Assigned Numbers Authority, like 80 for HTTP or 25 for email routing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the transport layer, TCP will also break the data up into “packets”. TCP attaches some “header” data to each packet so the receiving computer can reassemble the data and the sending computer can confirm all the data arrived without any mishaps. Back to our drive through window metaphor, the transport layer is stateful, it needs to keep track of each message and confirm it was received correctly. While being stateful is more of a burden, this part of the internet is what ensures the entire message reaches its destination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The packet header will also contain the source and destination IP address. Every computer has a unique IP address. An IP address (which is either a 32-bit numeric address (IPv4) is written in decimal as four numbers separated by periods or a 128-bit IP address (IPv6) written in hexadecimal and separated by colons. The IP addresses are mapped to our human readable ‘domain names’ with DNS. DNS is responsible for storing what IP address goes to what domain name. Let’s break down DNS a bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DNS (Domain Name System)&lt;/strong&gt; is a massive network of servers that catalogs every domain and IP address on the internet, including registration information, as well as their relation to other domains and web hosts. “DNS software” is a program that is installed on a web server and used to facilitate the transference of data related to the domain name system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;“name server”&lt;/strong&gt; is a web server that has DNS software installed on it, particularly a server that is managed by a web host that is specifically designated for managing the domain names that are associated with all of the hosting provider’s accounts. Name servers are often called DNS servers as well. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pcnames.com/articles/the-difference-between-dns-and-name-servers&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that we understand a bit of how these computers are finding each other with DNS let’s talk about the next layer, the Network Layer or “Internet Layer”. This layer is responsible for trying to send each packet as efficiently as possible. The internet layer does not care if packets get seperated or even if they get lost. It is the responsibility of TCP to check the packets all arrived and if not - try sending them again. The internet layer is really a series of connected router computers that work together to push each packet - in any order - closer to its destination. This layer is stateless, the internet will try to send anything, but it won’t keep track of success or failures. This is the stateless part of the internet that allows data to keep moving quickly. It’s fast and efficient, but might lose data, that’s where TCP is responsible for resending the lost packets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally we hit the &lt;strong&gt;“Data Link”&lt;/strong&gt; layer. Here some protocol like Ethernet or WiFi will be responsible from getting the data from the Internet to your physical computer. Ethernet and WiFI create a &lt;strong&gt;Local Area Network&lt;/strong&gt; (LAN). These are unique because a central router will act as the sole entrance/exit point to the internet. This router will be assigned that unique IP address that lets other computers find it. The router will be responsible for its own DNS, which will help it route traffic to the specific computer in the LAN, using the computer’s &lt;strong&gt;media access control address&lt;/strong&gt; (MAC address). A unique MAC address is given to your computer when it’s manufactured. Your computer’s IP address can change if your computer moves locations or networks, but its MAC address will not. You might think of it like your social security number will also be the same, but your home address will change if you move.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There we have it! TCP/IP can help us understand the fundamentals of how the internet works. Each layer and protocol contain more vertical knowledge you can deep dive into, I hope these fundamentals give you enough context to move forward!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2018 23:16:11 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2018/what-is-tcp-ip/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018/what-is-tcp-ip/</guid>
        
        <category>Devops</category>
        
        
        <category>Devops</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What’s Going on with Kubernetes Cluster Federation?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been involved in Kubernetes for a year and a half now. I have been drinking from a fire hose, trying to understand all things Kubernetes - the community direction, the proposals, the current solutions, the good, the bad and the ugly. With so many Special Interest Groups (SIGs) and such a broad community iterating so rapidly, I have come to realize this scope of project is hard for most individuals to have a deep understanding in every area. Considering this, I have tried to keep a “broad, but shallow” understanding of the project by attending the weekly community meeting and Kubecon. But recently I wanted to get a “deep” understanding of a specific part of the Kubernetes ecosystem: Cluster Federation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Federation was always an interesting concept to me, but I had never explored beyond the initial concept of: “it’s a magical way to control multiple kubernetes clusters - potentially in multiple cloud providers and on bare metal and move workloads throughout the cluster federation”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a disclaimer I should say, I do not consider myself a Federation “expert”. The following information is the result of about three weeks of experimenting with the Federation project, attending SIG meetings, watching old conference videos and reading blogs. I would encourage you to do your own research and get involved with the SIG Multicluster - they are super awesome and inviting in my experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the last 18 months I felt the community went from super stoked about Federation to radio silence. So what happened?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgflip.com/24z0fc.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;what happened to federation kubernetes&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to go on an exploration into the past, present and future of the project formerly known as Ubernetes to try and understand the current state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-community&quot;&gt;The Community&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To begin I wanted to go back in time, to understand the initial pitch and subsequent hype around the concept. I focused on conference videos and blogs from 2016 or later. These resources captured what I learned to be the “v1” phase of the Federation project. &amp;lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/pq9lbkmxpS8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/iframe&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also reading through the initial proposal will give you an idea of the federation problem space and scope: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kubernetes/community/blob/master/contributors/design-proposals/multicluster/federation.md&quot;&gt;Kubernetes Cluster Federation (previously nicknamed “Ubernetes”): Requirements Analysis and Product Proposal&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After wrapping my head around the origins of the project, I started learning about the massive changes and shifts that happened around the project in 2017. Here is a list of the highlights:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Federation project was incubated in the kubernetes/kubernetes project and released with Kubernetes v1.3.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ubernetes project renamed to Federation (more functionally descriptive)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Federation moved from Kubernetes/Kubernetes to Kubernetes/Federation in v1.9&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The SIG Federation renamed to Multicluster&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Kubefed introduced: A CLI tool to spin up Federation control plane&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“V1” of the federation problem was deemed “problematic” (my probably over-simplified understanding of why being: v1 was a monolithic “Kubernetes on Kubernetes” API, too closely resembling the single-cluster Kubernetes API, forward work would create a tangential and confusing meta orchestration layer)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“V2” conceptualized with more of a microservices approach, offering components that facilitate federation with a multicluster approach&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;SIG Multicluster released new projects: Cluster registry &amp;amp; KubeMCI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So looking back - what happened? Federation was proposed with an agenda in line with Kubernetes in general - abstracting the infrastructure away and creating a world where anyone can deploy anything, anywhere! Ironically in this pursuit of simplicity, Kubernetes (and Federation) have the potential to turn into a hulking monster of complexity. When Federation tried to essentially layer Kubernetes on Kubernetes - the potential for creating a two-headed monster was too real for many people in the community to accept. As a result, the Federation team went back to the drawing board to imagine a more loosely coupled, flexible solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kelsey Hightower’s keynote on Federation from Kubecon in April 2017 captures a more toned-down approach to Federation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/kwOvOLnFYck&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get a more detailed outline of the current state of SIG Multicluster check out this document: &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1V8NuRqDoZwugf5Tz8K-SFEJbQ4CCiCTZbU8UBzu8euk/edit?ts=5a7e1151#&quot;&gt;SIG Multicluster - Project Status&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;trying-the-project&quot;&gt;Trying the Project&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only did I want to understand the community dynamics and politics behind the project, I also want to learn how the project works. My preferred method of learning - dive in! I used several tutorials and projects as learning tools, each illuminating a different part of the Federation project for me. Depending on your familiarity with Kubernetes, I suggest completing the following tutorials, once or several times. If you are anything like me, new concepts will start to make sense with each pass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started with Kelsey Hightower’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kelseyhightower/kubernetes-cluster-federation&quot;&gt;“Cluster Federation (the Hard Way)”&lt;/a&gt;. Kelsey’s “hardway” tutorials are a great way to pop open the hood and poke around. He provides instruction to spin up a cluster Federation without using tools like Kubefed, which can obfuscate some of what is going on behind the scenes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After doing Federation “the hardway” I followed the K8s community guide to setting up a cluster Federation using &lt;a href=&quot;https://kubernetes.io/docs/tasks/federation/set-up-cluster-federation-kubefed/&quot;&gt;kubefed&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After these exercises I still one outstanding curiosity: to experiment with multi-cloud Federation. I had the best luck setting up multicloud Kubernetes Cluster Federation with this tutorial: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/font/k8s-example-apps/blob/master/pacman-nodejs-app/docs/pacman-nodejs-app-federated-multicloud.md&quot;&gt;Pac-Man Application On Federated Kubernetes Cluster Across Multiple Public Cloud providers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not gonna lie…I was feeling pretty godlike successfully coordinating multiple clusters on AWS, Azure and Google Cloud! My goal of seeing a cluster federation working across multiple clouds was realized. I have to extend a big thanks to the SIG Multicluster members for answering quite a few questions and recommending great resources. I am excited to see how the “V2” Federation API develops this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested in learning more, I suggest joining their Slack channel, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kubernetes/community/tree/master/sig-multicluster&quot;&gt;attending a SIG meeting&lt;/a&gt; or joining their mailing list.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2018 14:23:10 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2018/what-happened-to-kubernetes-cluster-federation/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018/what-happened-to-kubernetes-cluster-federation/</guid>
        
        <category>Kubernetes</category>
        
        
        <category>Kubernetes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Gitlab helped me realize I love CI/CD</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;moving-from-jenkins-ci-to-gitlab-ci&quot;&gt;Moving from Jenkins CI to Gitlab CI&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You folks probably know I am newish to tech (just hit my one year anniversary fulltime in the industry) and in the beginning the whole idea of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Continuous_integration&quot;&gt;CI&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Continuous_delivery&quot;&gt;CD&lt;/a&gt; seemed like this big, mysterious, robo-conveyor belt moving things from my personal computer to the cloud. But how!?!? But why!?!!? But what!?!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mystery was not aided by the fact we were using Jenkins (in my humble opinion). Now, I don’t have a ton of context in this CI/CD world, so I’m not going to knock Jenkins from a conceptual or technological level; but from a UI/UX level…they aren’t bending over backwards to make their users feel happy or comfortable. As a new user to Jenkins I found myself constantly lost or forgetting “where things were” and wondering why the primary info I desired: why the job failed, was so hard to dig up!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just figured; I’m a newb and CI/CD is a complicated product - so all CI/CD platforms must be this way. Then about 9 months into my career, after I was just starting to get competent with Jenkins, my team decided to swap to Gitlab CI. After a brief period of self-pity, that I would have to ramp up on another system, I really dug in and took on some big tickets to help me understand Gitlab’s CI/CD offering. I learned a ton from porting CI/CD pipelines from Jenkins to Gitlab. This allowed me to see the parallels, similarities and dissimilarities between the two products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thing first thing I had to wrap my head around was that Gitlab was both a “web based git repository manager” like Github AND a continuous integration &amp;amp; continuous delivery platform, like Jenkins. If you want to use Gitlab CI/CD you do must create an adjacent repo, you can’t just trigger CI/CD from Github (or where ever your code lives). There are tools to sync Github and Gitlab, if you don’t want to completely delete your project from Github.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even before I had experience with Gitlab, I noticed the UI/UX is FRESH! The interface is modern and very intuitive, I was able to “find” things quickly and remember the workflow after a long weekend.  Another cool aspect for our team is that Gitlab is Cloud Native out of the box. Running CI/CD in Kubernetes and containers is a first-class citizen. This creates a fluid experience for teams running CI in containers, compared to relying on a potentially fragile chain of plugins on Jenkins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;basic-concepts&quot;&gt;Basic Concepts&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a breakdown of the primary Gitlab CI/CD concepts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;pipeline-a-group-of-jobs-that-get-executed-in-stages&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pipeline&lt;/strong&gt;: a group of jobs that get executed in stages&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Defined in the .gitlab-ci.yml&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Triggered by events: usually git push; alternatives include scheduling &amp;amp; API hooks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;All jobs in a stage get executed in parallel&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If a job fails, the next stage is usually not started&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;job--scoped-work-necessary-to-complete-a-pipeline&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Job&lt;/strong&gt;:  scoped work necessary to complete a pipeline&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Defined in the .gitlab-ci.yml&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;runner-the-application-that-is-used-to-run-your-jobs-and-send-the-results-back-to-gitlab&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Runner&lt;/strong&gt;: the application that is used to run your jobs and send the results back to GitLab&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Written in Go&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Allows multiple jobs to run concurrently&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You select the runner that is right for your CI/CD environment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;executor-modules-used-to-run-your-builds-in-different-scenarios-we-use-kubernetes&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Executor&lt;/strong&gt;: modules used to run your builds in different scenarios (we use Kubernetes)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Calls the Kubernetes cluster API and creates a new Pod for each GitLab CI job&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The follow image depicts a “pipeline” with each individual “job”. Each section is a “stage”. The green check indicated the job passed.
&lt;img src=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/ci/img/pipelines.png&quot; alt=&quot;gitlab ci pipeline display&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next image is a different view of two pipelines. You can see all the pipeline metadata from this view and also restart or stop pipelines. 
&lt;img src=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/ci/img/pipelines_index.png&quot; alt=&quot;gitlab ci pipelines&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I absolutely had some fear after my experience with the complexities of Jenkins to learn a new CI/CD platform. In the end ramping up in Gitlab was a very painless…dare I say an enjoyable experience. Since I started using Gitlab I learned a bit about the company and really respect their &lt;a href=&quot;https://about.gitlab.com/community/&quot;&gt;community&lt;/a&gt; standards, openness and transparency - in addition to their proactive stance on building a platform that people really want. The frictionless nature of Gitlab has allowed me to iterate more quickly, experiment with testing or deployment concepts and really understand what is happening in my CI/CD environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh and I realized CI/CD is freaking awesome! It’s amazing what a difference a frictionless environment can make to creativity and productivity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2018 22:24:27 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2018/moving-from-jenkins-to-gitlab-CI/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018/moving-from-jenkins-to-gitlab-CI/</guid>
        
        <category>Kubernetes</category>
        
        
        <category>Kubernetes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Certified Kubernetes Administrator Exam (CKA)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve never been an “exam type”. Attending a liberal arts school like Sarah Lawrence College, then moving into a freelance motorcycle stunt riding career, I have found my comfort zone in creating big projects to prove my skills. So when my team at Samsung floated the idea of taking the brand-new &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cncf.io/certification/expert/&quot;&gt;“Certified Kubernetes Administrator”&lt;/a&gt; exam, I was intimidated - to say the least!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the Cloud Native Computing Foundation website, “The Certified Kubernetes Administrator (CKA) program was created by the Cloud Native Computing Foundation (CNCF), in collaboration with The Linux Foundation, to help develop the Kubernetes ecosystem.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started looking into what the exam would cover, which was exactly…everything. Here are the topics: Application Lifecycle Management, Installation, Configuration &amp;amp; Validation, Core Concepts, Networking, Scheduling, Security, Cluster Maintenance, Logging / Monitoring, Storage and Troubleshooting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point I had been working with Kubernetes for a year, but I just didn’t feel confident I had deep knowledge in all of these categories. Despite my uncertainty, this was an excellent opportunity to study up and test my knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-i-prepared&quot;&gt;How I prepared:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I started using VIM full time (the test is entirely terminal based and you have to be QUICK!).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I read the &lt;a href=&quot;https://kubernetes.io/docs/home/&quot;&gt;Kubernetes documentation&lt;/a&gt; and did the corresponding tutorials.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Keep in mind the cluster’s might be deployed in a way you aren’t familiar with - learn the &lt;a href=&quot;https://kubernetes.io/docs/concepts/overview/components/#master-components&quot;&gt;Kubernetes control plane fundementals&lt;/a&gt; so you can quickly get your footing in the exam clusters.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I brushed up on etcd and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/coreos/etcd/tree/master/etcdctl&quot;&gt;etcdctl&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I studied with my team - this was great to soak up other people’s expertise in certain areas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I’d done all I could to prepare and it was exam day. The exam was capped at 3 hours (I took the full 3 hours) and I was being watched through my video camera by a moderator (no drinks, notes or other people in the room). Throughout the test you are given tasks and various clusters in different states to perform these tasks on. It was actually pretty cool to work on and troubleshoot real clusters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;tips-for-during-the-exam&quot;&gt;Tips for during the exam:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Keep notes on each question, document things that didn’t work or half worked and if you finished the question with confidence.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Time cap each question, move on if you hit the time cap.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When you get through all the questions, go back through your notes and work on the questions you didn’t quite finished.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Check out the official breakdown of how each “problem category” is weighted. For example, if you think the question you are working on falls under “Core Concepts” (worth 19%) prioritize it over a “Logging / Monitoring” question (worth 5%).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Factor in one short break to stretch, drink water or use the restroom.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not going to say it was a breeze, but in the end and on my second try, I did pass the exam. I certainly would not have guessed a year ago, when I was still in bootcamp, that I would be a “Certified Kubernetes Administrator” by the following summer!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Special thanks to my awesome teammates at Samsung Cloud Native Computing Team for their support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.cncf.io/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/logo_cka_whitetext-2.png&quot; alt=&quot;CKA badge&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 15:24:27 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/certified-kubernetes-administrator-exam/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/certified-kubernetes-administrator-exam/</guid>
        
        <category>Kubernetes</category>
        
        
        <category>Kubernetes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ada: What to Expect</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;ada-developers-academy-getting-accepted-and-what-to-expect&quot;&gt;Ada Developers Academy: Getting Accepted and What to Expect&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“&lt;a href=&quot;http://adadevelopersacademy.org/&quot;&gt;Ada Developers Academy&lt;/a&gt; is a training program located in Seattle, Washington for women and non-binary people who want to become software developers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ada is tuition-free and is comprised of 6 months of full-time classroom training followed by 5 months in a paid industry internship.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ya, you read that right, Ada is a 11 month program that teaches you to code for free. You graduate with an internship on your resume and an extremely good chance of landing a job - quickly. Currently the program has a 97% job placement rate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might be thinking, what’s the catch? I graduated in February 2017 and am here to tell you, the only catch is, you gotta go all in. It’s a commitment: time, money, relationships, possibly your health and mental health. If you’re prepared and able to take a year, that year will undoubtedly change your life. You will learn more than you ever imagined, join an army of women bound for success in their new tech careers and get a high-paying job as an engineer, with your new, in-demand skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;get-accepted&quot;&gt;Get Accepted&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The application process is pretty long and difficult. If you can, carve a few days out to dedicate to the application. On the technical questions, I took about a week, answering the questions and revising my answers multiple times. Take your time with the answers, sleep on them, revise them, explain yourself, notice the details. For the character questions, be honest and articulate what makes you unique, what you’re passionate about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are waiting for an application window to open, take some online programming courses. I recommend Ruby or Python, there are good ones on Coursera or Codeacademy. Try some tutorials on Git and terminal commands. These will be helpful, but you do not need to know how to code to get into Ada.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ada-interviews&quot;&gt;Ada Interviews&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the in person interview portion, remember the people interviewing you are on your side. They are most likely volunteers who really believe in this program and the mission. Show them you care and you are dedicated. Describe things you have accomplished in the past, things you care deeply about, even if you think they are trivial - YOU DID IT, so be proud of that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They want to accept people who will not only succeed in the program, but go on to succeed in the industry. They want people who can not only hack it - but redefine the environments they enter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the technical in person interview, take a deep breath and remember they don’t expect you to KNOW all the answers, they are more interested in your thought process. Reason out loud, if you hit a deadend with your logic, start over and use what you learned to move forward. Try to think of it as a puzzle or game - not a test!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;once-accepted-hey---congrats&quot;&gt;Once Accepted (Hey - Congrats!)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the weeks you have between your acceptance letter and starting Ada - do your laundry, say goodbye to your friends, buy anything you need to survive for the year and do the jumpstart work they send you. Meetup with the other members of your cohort and sleep. For real.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The course portion will be a blur, you will feel behind, but you probably are not. Prepare yourself to be thrown in the deep end every Monday and just as you start to get your feet under you, Monday will come again and throw you straight back in the deep end. It’s fine, trust the teachers, trust the program and show up ready to learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Capstone project time will come up quick, be sure to create a detailed plan for your project with your professor. Recognize the time and resource limits. You will want to create something illustrious, but in the end if your project works - you win.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I chose a hardware/machine learning capstone - you can read about it &lt;a href=&quot;https://leahnp.github.io/2016/centaur-app/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. In the beginning of month I imagined a production ready app, but by the end of the month I was extremely proud of the single machine learning model I had created and the visual way I displayed my data. You can always revisit your capstone and add more features, so know when to call it quits and polish what you have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be proud of yourself, congratulate yourself and your fellow Adies and remember how damn far you have come!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;internships&quot;&gt;Internships&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Internship stress really starts with the company presentations, which will bite into your classroom time. Companies do their pitch and there are limited times provided to squeeze in as much networking as possible. If you’re anything like me (an introvert who loathes networking) this will be exhausting. Keep one thing in mind, you WILL get an internship. I was lucky and had an immediate interest in the Samsung Cloud Native Computing Team, while most of my cohort shied away from the systems-heavy job description, full of things we had not learned anything about during our time at Ada. I was quite vocal about my interest in that internship, which I do think helped me get placed there. But in the end, there is no way to know where you’re going, so sit back, don’t stress about it and be grateful to be given this rad opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you get placed at your internships, realize the end is near….&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hit the ground running, advocate for yourself and get some meaty projects to put on your resume. You will want something to talk about in your upcoming interviews. Do not kick back thinking you have “months”…get yours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;real-interviews&quot;&gt;Real Interviews&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was the hardest part for me. I am pretty cool headed and a realist, so I was able to not get too stressed before this point. The unfortunate truth is: technical interviews are terrible and the cards are stacked against you. Technical interviews are really setup for recent CS degree grads with an amazing internship on the resume to succeed. There is no way after doing computer programming for 7-8 months you can compete in that environment. So you need to bring something else to the table. Do you have skills from a past career? Talk about them. How can your diversity benefit the company? Talk about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Start studying for interviews as soon as possible, but realize you can’t cram 4 years of education in a few weeks. Just do the best you can. Leverage the Ada Network and be gracious. The companies supporting Ada believe in a future vision of a fully trained, diverse workforce creating better products for a broader consumer base. But right now…you are someone with the potential to be that workforce, only if someone takes a chance and invests in you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In your interviews show an openness to learn and an commitment to continually grow. If/when you get offers, negotiate. Know what is important to you and clearly state them. Always ask for more money and give the company reasons why they should make you a better offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;so-is-it-worth-it&quot;&gt;So is it worth it?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re looking for a change in careers, tech is a great choice. Usually tech companies are progressive, offer flexible schedules, pay well and these jobs are not going away anytime soon. I think Ada is one of the best ways to get into the industry if you can take the year. It’s free, it’s comprehensive, you not only get an education and you also get an amazing network of Adies to support you now and in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about the program or my experience, send me a note!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.geekwire.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/adadevelopersacademy.png&quot; alt=&quot;ada logo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2017 00:04:23 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/ada-developers-academy/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/ada-developers-academy/</guid>
        
        <category>Ada</category>
        
        
        <category>Ada</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Women’s March on Washington</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;womens-march-on-washington&quot;&gt;Women’s March on Washington&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has been a hard year. While I was involved in moving from one male dominated industry (motorsports) to another (tech); I was not-so-subtly reminded I can make every right professional move, work my ass off and probably still lose out to a white man with a much lesser resume.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve dealt with each blow to humanity with denial (he won’t be the nominee…he won’t become president….etc…), but when my mother suggested we march in Washington, I decided it was time to face the music. I needed to find a way to cope and a positive way forward. I booked a red-eye to NYC and a charter bus with &lt;a href=&quot;http://nownyc.org/&quot;&gt;NOW NYC&lt;/a&gt; to DC. My goal was to find some peace in the company of other empathic, supportive, inspiring individuals and find a way for me to start working for change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The day of the rally, I woke at 3am, took the subway to the bus meeting point and hopped on a bus bound for DC. In the still dark morning, we queued onto the southbound highway, already bumper to bumper with buses. The traffic grew heavier as we drew closer to DC and the sidewalks became packed with heavy streams of people entering the metro to get to downtown. We joined the queues to the metro, only to find each arriving train, one after the other already, entirely jam packed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/dud19rm.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Metro Station&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finally squeezed onto a train only to find the stations near the mall had been closed to overcrowding, so we were eventually dropped a few stops away. The doors opened at our stop and the platform - was already completely jammed, with so many people we couldn’t exit the station. The chanting and cheering start as we streamed the rally from the underground station.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finally made it above ground only to find more crowds. I was planning to meet my mother and father, but had to hike 25 blocks out of the way to find a way to circumvent the unpassable mobs of peaceful protesters. After two hours of urban hiking I made it to the meeting point and met my family - a stroke of luck considering the cell towers were overwhelmed and not working.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/4yqgKRx.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Women's March on Washington&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mom and Dad scouted an excellent location near the rally above Independence Ave where we could hear the speakers and entertainers. The speakers represented a wide and diverse population, reminding everyone we are the same through our diverse expressions. The crowds around DC were so vast, most could not access the rally and official march route, but they marched anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/nlRyWMm.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Women's March on Washington&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marching bands kept the energy pulsing through our tired and cold bodies. We slowly flowed, thick and steady and endless arteries, clogging the city, cars honked in support, chants called out, diversity and acceptance was for once, the norm. Love ruled all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We reminded each other, we were there, we supported one another and we were moving forward. The train rides home were full of “What’s next?” conversations. Get involved. Call your congressman. And most importantly, as Obama reminded us as he left his position at the white house, stop compalining on social media, join a club, volunteer, become involved in your community, become the community you want to be involved in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/CEfkfB4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Women's March on Washington&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/zSTlVXm.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Women's March on Washington&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2017 04:04:23 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/womens-march/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/womens-march/</guid>
        
        <category>Life</category>
        
        
        <category>Life</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Capstone Project: Centaur App</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;ada-developers-academy-capstone-project&quot;&gt;Ada Developers Academy Capstone Project&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Goal: Create an application that will record the motion data from my horse moving and identify if she was walking, trotting or cantering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/PAGEohk.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Example of walk, trot, canter&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After programming for 6 months, capstone time rolled around at Ada. I had this idea of a device that would track workouts on horseback - kind of like a horse fitbit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/q91R9dp.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;My Assistant&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ‘first generation’ hardware solution was a raspberry pi and accelerometer/gyroscope. A fun solution, but not ‘user friendly’ as you can see it taped to my saddle here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/qnEnMFB.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;raspberry pi on a horse&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I quickly moved onto version 2.0 - my phone. An easy solution using the android accelerometer function. I wrote a front end to capture the data points, then load them to the backend for the algorithm to process. The app was written in Node.js and Javascript.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used Python and a machine learning library called scikit learn to process the data. After training a k-Nearest Neighbor algorithm I could quickly and accurately categorize thousands of data points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/lEfHpri.gif&quot; alt=&quot;data visualization&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the algorithm had done its work I could display time spent in each gait to the client.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/xLjwVuC.gif&quot; alt=&quot;The app&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project was an amazing, immersive experience, truly the icing on the cake that was my time in the classroom at Ada Developers Academy. I can’t believe in such a short time I learned the skills to take on a project like this and look forward to expanding my skills even more during my internship at Samsung SDSA on the Cloud Native Computing Team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/TfdN0eW.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Finished project!&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2016 06:04:23 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2016/centaur-app/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2016/centaur-app/</guid>
        
        <category>Ada</category>
        
        
        <category>Ada</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Kubecon 2016</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;my-first-developers-conference&quot;&gt;My first developers conference!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After working since September on the Samsung Cloud Native Computing team, I had the chance to go to Kubecon in Seattle, WA. We use Kubernetes daily so Kubecon was a great chance to see how other companies are using Kubernetes and the technologies growing around it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Cloud Native Computing Foundation posted a blog I wrote about my experience &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cncf.io/blog/2016/11/18/diversity-scholarship-series-time-cloudnativecon-2016&quot;&gt;HERE&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2016 03:04:23 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2016/kubecon-2016/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2016/kubecon-2016/</guid>
        
        <category>Kubernetes</category>
        
        
        <category>Kubernetes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>From Wheelies to Kubernetes</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;i-want-a-new-career&quot;&gt;I want a new career.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I decided I didn’t want to stunt motorcycles professionally for the rest of my life. It had begun to feel more like…work…if you know what I mean. And if I have to work for a living I wanted a job where breaking your neck is a less likely outcome of the day to day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to do something quantifiable, a job where my skills can be measured and have a clear market value. No more art, performance or marketing - I wanted a job where I could deliver a product and see it succeed in production (then get well paid for it, end of story).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I never considered computer programming, it just wasn’t on my list of possibilities. In the middle of this search for my next career I had started 3D modeling (which is relatively technical), then I started animating a few things (a bit more technical…you see where this is going) and finally I thought, it would be pretty cool to manipulate this stuff on a code level. So I enrolled in my first computer programming course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To my surprise I actually liked solving coding problems. I took a few more online courses, but now, how would I get a job in an industry typically reserved for Stanford grads and ‘math people’ when my resume read ‘wheelies all around the world’. Enter, &lt;a href=&quot;http://adadevelopersacademy.org/&quot;&gt;Ada Developers Academy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ada is a free, highly selective, year long web developer program for women. Ada’s primary mission is changing the face of the technology industry. Most of the students including myself, never thought of computer science as an option because we have no/few role models in the industry. I like riding horses, motorcycles, yoga, fashion, hiking, travel, language - so is there a place for me in tech? Apparently Ada thought there was and I was accepted. I started class in February 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ada-developers-academy---accepted&quot;&gt;Ada Developers Academy - Accepted!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first 7 months of the program are spent in a classroom learning everything from Git to Ruby to Node to Test Driven Development. The seventh month is spent working on a solo capstone project. I created an app called Centaur that tracked the movement of my horse and used machine learning to identify when she was walk, trot or cantering during a training session. How far I had come in just a half year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last 5 month of Ada is spent in an internship at one of their many sponsoring companies. I was placed on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.samsungsdsa.com/cloud-infrastructure_kubernetes&quot;&gt;Cloud Native Computing Team&lt;/a&gt; at Samsung SDSA. I am half way into the internship and am working on a centralized logging system for a Kubernetes cluster (so many words in that sentence that I didn’t know the meaning of a few short months ago).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s my story, from wheelies and burnouts to employable in an industry that is relevant, aggressively hiring and offers diverse options around the world working with just about anything you can think of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the industry still has a ways to go regarding diversity, I have come to see how I do have a place in tech and how I can apply all my bizarre skills I have learned in my unconventional life to solve problems and build products in a way your classically trained CS student cannot.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2016 10:04:23 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2016/from-wheelies-to-kubernetes/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2016/from-wheelies-to-kubernetes/</guid>
        
        <category>Ada</category>
        
        
        <category>Ada</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
