<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Leah Petersen</title>
    <description>Motorcycle stunt woman turned developer, software engineer intern on the Samsung Cloud Native Computing Team.</description>
    <link>http://leahnp.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://leahnp.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2017 13:21:15 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2017 13:21:15 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Women’s March on Washington</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;womens-march-on-washington&quot;&gt;Women’s March on Washington&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has been a hard year. While I was involved in moving from one male dominated industry (motorsports) to another (tech); I was not-so-subtly reminded I can make every right professional move, work my ass off and probably still lose out to a white man with a much lesser resume.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve dealt with each blow to humanity with denial (he won’t be the nominee…he won’t become president….etc…), but when my mother suggested we march in Washington, I decided it was time to face the music. I needed to find a way to cope and a positive way forward. I booked a red-eye to NYC and a charter bus with &lt;a href=&quot;http://nownyc.org/&quot;&gt;NOW NYC&lt;/a&gt; to DC. My goal was to find some peace in the company of other empathic, supportive, inspiring individuals and find a way for me to start working for change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The day of the rally, I woke at 3am, took the subway to the bus meeting point and hopped on a bus bound for DC. In the still dark morning, we queued onto the southbound highway, already bumper to bumper with buses. The traffic grew heavier as we drew closer to DC and the sidewalks became packed with heavy streams of people entering the metro to get to downtown. We joined the queues to the metro, only to find each arriving train, one after the other already, entirely jam packed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finally squeezed onto a train only to find the stations near the mall had been closed to overcrowding, so we were eventually dropped a few stops away. The doors opened at our stop and the platform - was already completely jammed, with so many people we couldn’t exit the station. The chanting and cheering start as we streamed the rally from the underground station.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finally made it above ground only to find more crowds. I was planning to meet my mother and father, but had to hike 25 blocks out of the way to find a way to circumvent the unpassable mobs of peaceful protesters. After two hours of urban hiking I made it to the meeting point and met my family - a stroke of luck considering the cell towers were overwhelmed and not working.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mom and Dad scouted an excellent location near the rally above Independence Ave where we could hear the speakers and entertainers. The speakers represented a wide and diverse population, reminding everyone we are the same through our diverse expressions. The crowds around DC were so vast, most could not access the rally and official march route, but they marched anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marching bands kept the energy pulsing through our tired and cold bodies. We slowly flowed, thick and steady and endless arteries, clogging the city, cars honked in support, chants called out, diversity and acceptance was for once, the norm. Love ruled all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We reminded each other, we were there, we supported one another and we were moving forward. The train rides home were full of “What’s next?” conversations. Get involved. Call your congressman. And most importantly, as Obama reminded us as he left his position at the white house, stop compalining on social media, join a club, volunteer, become involved in your community, become the community you want to be involved in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/sT46AEB.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Women's March on Washington&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/dud19rm.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Metro Station&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/CEfkfB4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Women's March on Washington&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/nlRyWMm.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Women's March on Washington&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/zSTlVXm.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Women's March on Washington&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/4yqgKRx.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Women's March on Washington&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2017 04:04:23 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://leahnp.github.io/2017/womens-march/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://leahnp.github.io/2017/womens-march/</guid>
        
        <category>Life</category>
        
        
        <category>Life</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Capstone Project: Centaur App</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;ada-developers-academy-capstone-project&quot;&gt;Ada Developers Academy Capstone Project&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Goal: Create an application that will record the motion data from my horse moving and identify if she was walking, trotting or cantering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/PAGEohk.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Example of walk, trot, canter&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After programming for 6 months, capstone time rolled around at Ada. I had this idea of a device that would track workouts on horseback - kind of like a horse fitbit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/q91R9dp.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;My Assistant&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ‘first generation’ hardware solution was a raspberry pi and accelerometer/gyroscope. A fun solution, but not ‘user friendly’ as you can see it taped to my saddle here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/qnEnMFB.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;raspberry pi on a horse&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I quickly moved onto version 2.0 - my phone. An easy solution using the android accelerometer function. I wrote a front end to capture the data points, then load them to the backend for the algorithm to process. The app was written in Node.js and Javascript.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used Python and a machine learning library called scikit learn to process the data. After training a k-Nearest Neighbor algorithm I could quickly and accurately categorize thousands of data points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/lEfHpri.gif&quot; alt=&quot;data visualization&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the algorithm had done its work I could display time spent in each gait to the client.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/xLjwVuC.gif&quot; alt=&quot;The app&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project was an amazing, immersive experience, truly the icing on the cake that was my time in the classroom at Ada Developers Academy. I can’t believe in such a short time I learned the skills to take on a project like this and look forward to expanding my skills even more during my internship at Samsung SDSA on the Cloud Native Computing Team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/TfdN0eW.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Finished project!&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2016 06:04:23 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://leahnp.github.io/2016/centaur-app/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://leahnp.github.io/2016/centaur-app/</guid>
        
        <category>Ada</category>
        
        
        <category>Ada</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Kubecon 2016</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;my-first-developers-conference&quot;&gt;My first developers conference!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After working since September on the Samsung Cloud Native Computing team, I had the chance to go to Kubecon in Seattle, WA. We use Kubernetes daily so Kubecon was a great chance to see how other companies are using Kubernetes and the technologies growing around it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Cloud Native Computing Foundation posted a blog I wrote about my experience &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cncf.io/blog/2016/11/18/diversity-scholarship-series-time-cloudnativecon-2016&quot;&gt;HERE&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2016 03:04:23 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://leahnp.github.io/2016/kubecon-2016/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://leahnp.github.io/2016/kubecon-2016/</guid>
        
        <category>Kubernetes</category>
        
        
        <category>Kubernetes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>From Wheelies to Kubernetes</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;i-want-a-new-career&quot;&gt;I want a new career.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I decided I didn’t want to stunt motorcycles professionally for the rest of my life. It had begun to feel more like…work…if you know what I mean. And if I have to work for a living I wanted a job where breaking your neck is a less likely outcome of the day to day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to do something quantifiable, a job where my skills can be measured and have a clear market value. No more art, performance or marketing - I wanted a job where I could deliver a product and see it succeed in production (then get well paid for it, end of story).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I never considered computer programming, it just wasn’t on my list of possibilities. In the middle of this search for my next career I had started 3D modeling (which is relatively technical), then I started animating a few things (a bit more technical…you see where this is going) and finally I thought, it would be pretty cool to manipulate this stuff on a code level. So I enrolled in my first computer programming course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To my surprise I actually liked solving coding problems. I took a few more online courses, but now, how would I get a job in an industry typically reserved for Stanford grads and ‘math people’ when my resume read ‘wheelies all around the world’. Enter, &lt;a href=&quot;http://adadevelopersacademy.org/&quot;&gt;Ada Developers Academy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ada is a free, highly selective, year long web developer program for women. Ada’s primary mission is changing the face of the technology industry. Most of the students including myself, never thought of computer science as an option because we have no/few role models in the industry. I like riding horses, motorcycles, yoga, fashion, hiking, travel, language - so is there a place for me in tech? Apparently Ada thought there was and I was accepted. I started class in February 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ada-developers-academy---accepted&quot;&gt;Ada Developers Academy - Accepted!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first 7 months of the program are spent in a classroom learning everything from Git to Ruby to Node to Test Driven Development. The seventh month is spent working on a solo capstone project. I created an app called Centaur that tracked the movement of my horse and used machine learning to identify when she was walk, trot or cantering during a training session. How far I had come in just a half year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last 5 month of Ada is spent in an internship at one of their many sponsoring companies. I was placed on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.samsungsdsa.com/cloud-infrastructure_kubernetes&quot;&gt;Cloud Native Computing Team&lt;/a&gt; at Samsung SDSA. I am half way into the internship and am working on a centralized logging system for a Kubernetes cluster (so many words in that sentence that I didn’t know the meaning of a few short months ago).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s my story, from wheelies and burnouts to employable in an industry that is relevant, aggressively hiring and offers diverse options around the world working with just about anything you can think of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the industry still has a ways to go regarding diversity, I have come to see how I do have a place in tech and how I can apply all my bizarre skills I have learned in my unconventional life to solve problems and build products in a way your classically trained CS student cannot.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2016 10:04:23 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://leahnp.github.io/2016/from-wheelies-to-kubernetes/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://leahnp.github.io/2016/from-wheelies-to-kubernetes/</guid>
        
        <category>Ada</category>
        
        
        <category>Ada</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
